Okay, the next talk of Foundation Track
will begin in two minutes.
Dr. Carola will give a speech with
"It's all about the domain, honey!
Experiences from 15 years of the Domain-Driven Design"
Okay, so you can scan the QR code
on the top right and you can go to Slido and
ask some questions. So, let's welcome Dr. Carola, Hello!
Good morning phone, good morning. I mean good
morning from europe you know we have morning here.
Yeah, it's afternoon here.
Yeah, perfect.
Should I start um sharing my slides
Sure! Okay, so Carola can you try show your slides?
Yes sure here we go.
Can you see them?
Yes very good perfect you can start your speech, thank you.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Hi everybody, um in this talk I will show
you how to build systems in a way that makes sense
for the business and um how Domain-Driven Design
can help you to do that. Um, my name is Carola
and on Twitter you can find me under my
handle @cairolali. I have studied computer science
at the University of Hamburg and I gained my
diploma in 1995 and since then I have done a
lot of programming in C++, in Java even in
Visual Basic and in C# of course as well and
I have done a lot of consulting taking planes to
visit my customers and i work as an architect and
architectin this is the German female version
of an architect and in 2008 I handed in my
PhD thesis with the title "Complexity of
Software Architecture" I then turned um all
the things i found out in my doctor's thesis into
a business model for my company um we evaluate
the complexity of software architectures and
check whether they are sustainable and how many
technical depth they have. All this is written
down in my book "Sustainable Software Architecture"
with many examples and pitfalls that one
encounters on the way to a good architecture.
I have been working since 1999 at my
company called WPS Workplace Solutions.
We started with 12 coders and today we have 130 coders
in the company. We really love modular software
systems with a good architecture and we have been
working with Domain-Driven design since 2004.
We are located in Germany in the middle
of europe and we are sitting in Hamburg
and in Berlin as well Berlin is the capital
of Germany as some of you might know.
We are building enjoyable business software
this means um software that the user really
loves to work with like this one here you can
see on the slide this is a software to coordinate
the construction works on the roads of different
large towns. There are three towns
in Germany that are using this system today
and one part of this system is a touch table
to make it possible that people from different
organizations from towns, from water pipe companies,
from telecommunication companies that they meet
and discuss their construction work together
and enjoyable business software from
our point of view has a beautiful user interface
but also a good architecture since only a
system with a good sustainable architecture
can as well offer a long life good user
interface and good procedures.
If we want to have a sustainable
architecture why do we want that well
we want that because we want our software to have
a long useful life and thus pay off our investment
that we did in the beginning and from my point
of view software will only pay off our investment
if we have the lowest possible
maintenance cost and extension cost.
So, if it's easy to change the system if it's
easy to extend the system then our investment
was a good one and we will have a system that
lives for a long time and this is only possible if
the system has a sustainable architecture if
it's easy to understand, easy to change and
easy to extend. This saves time and this saves
money if we have an architecture like that.
This diagram illustrates our goal visually we
want to be able to keep adding a similar number
of features to our system for a long time to come.
On the y-axis you see numbers
from 0 to 20. Those are the numbers of
features that we can deliver per release and
we want to have a high constant number there. you
can see it starts around 16 features per release
and if you follow the green path then you stay
on the same level with the features that you
can deliver per release but complexity and
technical depth often prevent us from doing
so and we end up with a sad norm down there the
curve goes down and we are not able to deliver
many features anymore per release, which
is really frustrating for the users
and as well for the development team of course.
During and after my PhD we have analyzed a great
many systems of different ages, sizes and
programming languages you can see various
programming languages here on this on
the slide. In the middle of the slide,
there is a pie chart showing how many systems
of which size we have analyzed. So if you look
at the light blue there is 120 in there so
we were able to analyze 120 systems and the
size is annotated on the side. These systems had
a size up to hundred thousand lines of code.
So quite small hundred thousand lines of code
those are systems like apps on smartphones or
the first version of a software system. But out
there are systems that are much larger you can
see on the the purple ones half a million lines
of code we have looked at 150 systems of that size
and they are also out there a lot of systems
even bigger 1 million 5 million 15 million
so there are a lot of quite huge systems out there
and many of these systems are developed in modern
programming languages like Java, C# and so
on, but they frustrate their developers a lot.
Because they have accumulated technical depth and
complexity over the years of their construction
and, unfortunately, some of them are micro service
architectures. The great new architectural style
that was supposed to solve all our problems
when we were told about it around 2012.
It used to be that people would call
me and say: "Carola, we have a legacy system
and we need help. It's getting more and more
expensive and slower and slower to maintain.
Can you help us break the system into
microservices?" So this was the past.
Today, people call me and they say: "Ah, Carola,
we have a microservice architecture and
maintenance is getting more and more
expensive and slow. Uh, what have we done wrong?"
Yes, what is wrong? Well, with a lot of microservice
architectures people have made the same mistake
the same mistakes they made with monoliths before.
I stole this diagram here from Simon Brown because
it explains so well that what was forgotten.
On the y-axis you have modularity, and on the
x-axis you have the number of deployment units.
So, on the left side the two systems have
just one deployment unit on the right side you have
various or larger number of deployment units
and if you follow the y-axis, those two systems on
the bottom have low modularity and the ones
up there have high modularity. And what people
forgot was that a good architecture is actually
about creating independent modules. Therefore,
a modular architecture is actually
the opposite to a big ball of mud.
In a modular architecture independence of
modules is is the top priority, so even if you
have just one deployment unit you should have
a modular monolith, which is on the left side
on the top. If you don't do that, you will
end up with a big ball of mud. Not modular,
and just one number of deployment units. This is
the one monolithic big ball of mud down there.
No matter if you have a monolith
or a great number of deployment units,
what is shown on the y-axis. If you don't have
independent modules, you have a big ball of mud
as well in a distributed system, with a lot of
deployment units, and that is much worse than a
monolithic big bowl of mud. If modularity is not
your top priority, your system will probably look like this.
This diagram on the right side shows a
class cycle this is a strongly connected components.
Each square is a class and these classes are
connected with lines this is where they're used
each other and the different colors in the
diagram show that they come from 10 different modules.
This system was developed 15 years ago, I
mean it is in development since 15 years and today
and the whole system has 3 million lines
of code, which means that this tangled
class cycle that has half a million lines
of code takes a big part in the system.
30 developers have been working on this system
for 15 years. If you change one class in this
cycle you have to check the whole cyclic
structure to exclude possible side effects.
This greatly slows down
maintenance and enhancement.
Another example even bigger 10 million lines of
code developed in Java over the last 20 years.
When they started, nobody told them about
modularity, monoliths and microservices.
This was in 2000. These ideas did not even
exist at that time and you see the result
what you see there is 90 modules and they are
strongly connected you see arcs on the left
side and on the right side. They all need each
other this is as well a real big ball of mud
and of course for the team a whole lot of extra
work for maintenance and enhancement. What has
happened here? Nobody has reduced or controlled the
dependencies in these complex structures, and what
can we do to prevent prevent this in
our micro service architectures, well,
we do have very old principles at hand to
prevent the big ball of mud in our architecture
this is high cohesion and lose coupling. Within
a module the classes or packages should work
together to fulfill one responsibility. This
responsibility connects them strongly together
and creates high cohesion. Other responsibilities
should be separated into their own module,
and outside of the module we want lose coupling
which means actually low coupling. One module
doesn't need much from another module. A module
should be complete from a domain point of view.
This is what Domain-Driven Design is talking
about as well. From outside of the module,
only relevant features should be visible and
accessible. Details of the implementation should
remain hidden, and this is why we call this
information hiding. A good modular architecture
that follows these principles would look like this.
We see here, three modules each of them should have
one responsibility and therefore have high
cohesion within. The key point is that we should
build this architecture in such a way that we have
as little coupling as possible between the modules.
But, but, this is only possible if there
is an idea of a domain architecture.
Domain-Driven Design has given us the
knowledge to create independent modules.
One module for the sales context as you
can see here on the slide, and another one
for the support context. This is such a
wonderful idea, and it works. It creates
modules that have high coercion and low coupling,
which means dependency control. But unfortunately,
not many systems have a domain architecture.
The other day, a client called me and said:
"Carola, we need help. We are having a micro service
architecture." Woohoo yes! I thought inside of myself.
And he continued: "We are having a
microservice architecture for our platform
where customers can sell their second-hand
vehicles and we have 270 microservices."
Oh this is quite a lot I thought. "And what
is the problem, well, if we want to change
something in the database. We have to discuss
this with all teams." What? What does this mean?
Well we looked at the thing, and each
microservice was using a library called "model-jar"
I ask them what this is, and they say: "Well,
that's the interface to the database you know.
The one and only database." When the second
microservice was built, they thought
that they could just reuse the work
of the first team on the domain model.
So they took the "model-jar", enhanced it for their
purpose and ended up with an overall domain model.
I have an example for you with a similar
problem where we try to find a solution.
I will explain the diagram to you in a second
but i will tell you the story before. A company
called us to look at their architecture
and help them to divide it into microservices,
and I asked them. "Well, what kind of architecture
do you have?" And normally people tell me: "We have a
layered architecture." But this one was different.
They said: "Our architecture follows use cases."
This is a criterion from the domain and I
thought finally no layered architecture
this will be exciting. And what
you see here on the slide
is the architecture that we put on the source
code with a tool. This tool is called "Sotograph".
For each use case, we have created a rectangle
and written the name of the use case next to it.
As you can see here, mailing, import
export, remove, startup and so on.
The dependencies between the systems parts that
are programmed into the source code as you know
are shown on the right side of the diagram.
The green arcs go downwards, so they represent
relationships from top to bottom, so some class
in the mailing use case is using something from
the import export use case. The red arcs colors
are not important at the moment. The red arcs
represent relationships from bottom to top, so
the remove use case there is a class in there
that needs something or that calls another
class from the import export use case.
After collecting the use cases, we looked at
the dependencies and we thought, well, maybe
mailing, import, export and remove. They could form
one microservice because they need each
other of course and then there is a gap.
But, if you look downwards you find
something which is quite strange, because,
down there, there is a part of the system called
"model", and you guess it this is the equivalent
of the "model-jar", I told them, well, this is not
a good idea if you wanted to cut your system into
microservices. We have to do something about
this and so we tried to distribute the classes
that are in this "model-jar" to the other
to the use cases so we took classes in here and
moved them upwards, some to the mailing, some to the
import export, where they probably belong because
they belong to this part of the system
and they form the bases in there.
So, we started and i think we
stopped when we put some classes
into your calculation because then
the thing already looked like.
As you can see on the right side. We allocated
model classes to the other to the use cases
and all these extra relationships dependencies
appeared. They were all hidden in the model. So you
can see now that mailing is as well has as well
connections to report and to editing many many
new dependencies they were all hidden, so what
we can see here is another big ball of mud.
So please, if you are building, or
having a micro service architecture.
Try to divide your domain into sub-domains with
small models. Try to create separate models,
because then you will allow independent changes.
You will have high coercion and loose
coupling and your team can work independently. Your
teams, the different teams for each microservices.
Because each model and each sub-domain should be
small enough to be programmed by just one team.
Otherwise your team will feel like the chickens on
the right side. These chickens have eaten pieces of
bread, but unfortunately some children have tied
those bread pieces together with a rope, and
after swallowing them. The chickens are no longer
independent and they might even die together, so,
let's look at a solution here. This is a banking
example, a bank with three business areas.
Account Managing, Credit Business and Security Business.
These three areas use the same classes: Account,
Customer, Credit and Security" to fulfill their
work, so one big "model-jar" for the whole system.
If we want to break them down to the bottom
of the domain model. We have to have much more
specific domain classes, "Account" and "Customer"
are over here in the "Account Managing" and we
as well need "Credit Customer" and "Credit Account"
as and "Security Account" and "Security Customer".
If you follow this advice, you will have separate
models for all your modules and each team can work
freely on their own domain model. Doesn't that
sound great? Yes. But how do we get there? Well,
we have to change our understanding of software
development. In many organizations, that I have
visited. The responsibilities are clearly
distributed. There's the role of the developers,
and the role of the architect is understood like
this. Developer and architect are responsible for
technical questions. Their job is to define which
programming language is used, which frameworks
and infrastructure is applied, which database to
use. The domain knowledge is something that the
business analysts have to deal with, however.
This division of responsibility will not work.
If we want our software to be structured according to
domain related domain related criterias. To have a
domain related structure we have to make sure
that the software has its roots in the domain.
And that the software is reflecting, a reflection
of the domain. Because at the end, the source code
only contains the understanding of the developers.
Not the requirements written down in the backlog
by the business analysts. The source code is
the written down understanding that programmers
have of the domain, nothing else. That's exactly
what Domain-Driven Design wants to help us with.
The goal of software development is to
translate the domain knowledge into software.
To understand the domain properly, we have
to talk to the domain experts. They have the
domain knowledge in their head. But, we have
to do this in a language they understand.
If not we will suffer from the model
monopoly. This is a well-described problem
in psychology. If you use a notation, that
transports your understanding of something
to another person, and you use a notation that only
you know. You will have a monopoly on the model.
A model like this for example, this is a, of course,
an extreme example but the underlying message.
Of the model monopoly is, if you show a model to
someone in a notation that is new for this person,
it is very difficult for the other person
to understand this model. The notation you are
using for the model is a new language, that the
user would have to learn to understand and
give feedback. This will result in a feedback
like: "Oh, yeah this looks good, quite complicated.
I see you thought a lot about it." This is
what users say in a case like that, and then you
end up with a software system that does not fit
the needs of your user. How do we get to
communicate with results that our users understand.
What should we do? Well, Domain-Driven Design
recommends us to explore the domain together
with users and developers in workshops.
Two techniques have developed in recent years in the
Domain-Driven Design environment: "Event Storming",
and "Domain Storytelling". These are both workshop
techniques that facilitate collaborative modeling.
For an event storming session, we meet with the
user and developers and model the process in
the domain with sticky notes on the wall. Each
sticky note represent a domain event.
All particip participants are invited to stick
notes, which are then discussed and sorted
with the whole group afterwards. This way, you get
a quick overview of the process without thinking
about the software. Today, of course we are
doing Event Storming remotely on a "Mirror" board.
In a session for Domain Storytelling, we also
meet with the users and developers and model the
process from the domain with actors, who exchange
domain objects and concepts. Today we also do this
remotely with an open source tool, called "Domain Story Modeler"
Let's look at this with an example.
This is a domain story for a small art house
cinema. In this little program cinema, there is
the cinema manager and the ticket agent. Once a
week, in this little cinema is issued a new weekly
schedule for the next week. The process starts
in the upper left corner over here, when the
advertising agency sends the plan for the
advertising bookings. Once the cinema manager has
received this plan, he starts working on the
weekly schedule with his super great legacy system, cinesmall.
The small yellow flash on
the icon of the weekly schedule indicates
that the cinesmall software is used here. Next, the
cinema manager gets the plan for the possible film
shows from the film distributor, and he looks at
the national wide number of visitors. He negotiates
with the film distributor which film he can get
and finally he finalizes the weekly schedule.
Our legacy system, cinesmall, then generates
auditorium plans and the ticket agent can start
selling tickets for the new scheduled film shows.
The customer comes to the cinema and asks for
tickets for a certain film show. The ticket
agent checks the auditorium plan to see if he
can find suitable seats in the auditorium for the
desired film show, and and he then sells the
seats to the customer. This is very domain specific
as you can see. You don't find any technical terms
in this domain story. This is because Domain-Driven
Design asks us to be aware, that the users speak a
different language than we do, it's not good if
we impose our technical language on them, that
would also be a kind of model monopoly, in which
we use a model, that the user does not understand.
No, we have to immerse ourselves into the
language of the domain experts and learn it.
Of course not everything, but only the part that
we want to map in our software. The part in which
our software this system should support the
users. And what happens then in the software?
Are we sticking to our
technical terms in the software,
in the source code? No, we also use the
domain specific terms in the source code.
Domain-Driven design calls this a ubiquitous
language, a language that we use in all
communication if we speak, if we write, if we create
diagrams and if we program in our source code.
Of course, the domain specific ubiquitous
language is only used in the domain
core of the application. In the technical areas, we
continue to use our technical programming language.
Sorry, okay. But now, we have a domain application
core and I thought we want to have separate
domain models in the architecture with
high cohesion and low coupling, right?
How do we get that to achieve this? Domain-Driven
Design taught us the strategic design.
Our software system supports
users in their work in a domain.
Domain-Driven Design tells us that in a domain,
above a certain size there should be sub-domains,
that can help us to divide our
software into bounded contexts.
Each bounded context sets explicit boundaries for
individual domain oriented paths in the software.
And as well, in the team organization, each
bounded context is handled by exactly one team.
We do all this, because our goal,
you remember, is high cohesion and
lose coupling for our bounded context. Let's
go back to the process in the cinema and see
what we can do there. You remember this, if you
look closely at this process, you can see there
are actually two entries, that is two triggers
that set different parts of the process in motion.
This is an important criterion that
they could be two sub-domains in here.
You see the two triggers on the left and on
the right. In addition, the two sub-processes
are also decoupled in terms of time. The left
one is performed once a week the weekly schedule,
and the right one, whenever the customer
comes to the cinema.
So in large cinemas there are
also department for these two sub-process,
the cinema management and the ticket sales.
The next very important indicator in here is found
in the middle, when the left sub-process is over,
there is a flow of information in one direction
into the other sub-process. The flow of information
is the weekly schedule and then the process
continues with the ticket sale. A way back is
not possible. This is a very very strong indicator
of a boundary between two bounded contexts,
two sub-domains. The work in one sub-domain is done,
and the result is passed on to another sub-domain.
In the second sub-domain, work is continued
on the result, or with the result. Finally,
you can use this example to make another
point from Domain-Driven Design clear.
Domain-Driven Design assumes that terms
in different sub-domains can mean different things
and we can also imagine that here
for our cinema. The customer looks at a
weekly schedule to find out about the planned
film shows. This weekly schedule is much less
detailed than the weekly schedule that the
cinema manager is working on. He notes the
cleaning time of the cinema halls and
the ice cream sellers and much more.
So let's summarize. We can cut the domain
into sub-domains according to boundaries in
the business processes. Good indicators are the
information flow as you have seen the process
rhythms or the process triggers. We can cut the
domain according to different uses of key concepts
in the domain or as well by departments
in the organization or groups of experts.
So what does that mean for our architecture
with the domain core and the technical
separated from the domain core? We get a domain
core that is divided into domain modules with
separate domain models and separate domain and
application services. What would a solution in
software look like for our cinema if we split it
into two bounded contexts according to these rules?
In a good solution we would have two
bounded contexts, Cinema Manager and
Ticket Sales. The bounded context Cinema
Manager would provide a user interface
for scheduling the weekly schedule.
This user interface works on a service
that allows you to schedule movies in theaters
schedule advertising for movies and
much more. The service itself uses the weekly
schedule and the auditorium plan to do its work.
The bounded context Ticket Sales would provide
a user interface as well. But for the Ticket Sales,
it works on a service itself and this service
uses the weekly schedule the auditorium plan
and the tickets of course to communicate with
each other and the two bounded contexts
in exchange the weekly schedule and the auditorium
plan. But this processing between the two bounded
contexts is done as in chronically. They don't
depend on each other. They are loosely coupled.
A bad solution would be to divide the domain
according to the entities involved in the process.
Here we will need direct coupling in
this solution. In a solution that is bad, we
would have a "Service Weekly Schedule" and a "Service
Auditorium Plan", one service for each entity.
Both entities would be protected by services and
their interface, and the methods that are necessary
to process the respective entities. Because the
methods are now each assigned to the service for
the entity at least the ticket sale user interface
must work synchronously with both services.
In addition there must be another service
for the tickets somewhere. Comparing these
these two solutions, we see loose
coupled bounded contexts on
the left green side and strongly coupled system
parts on the right side. Domain-Driven Design
recommends us, the left green side and strongly and
not to do strongly coupled systems on the right side.
If you go the left green way, you have to
live with the fact that you have the same entities
in different boundary compounded contexts. The
weekly schedule is presented in both contexts.
You can see that and the auditorium
plan as well. But what is with reuse then?
We have all learned in our software
engineering courses that we
should do dry. Dry a principle don't repeat
yourself and don't have duplicated code
and luckily enough. Domain-Driven Design speaks
about this as well. Imagine you are building
a system for four different sub-domains. In the old
times, companies have organized the work like this,
a head team, a team for the body, a team
for the legs and a team for the tail.
Well, there were a lot of interfaces between
these teams. They have to talk a lot and to
rely on each other to fulfill their jobs. You see
all the the dependencies, all the errors there.
After a while, reuse starts to take place.
This is almost inevitable the
body team finds out that there are things
that all body teams need, and the lag team
puts together the yellow and
the blue part, and the tails create
reusable systems as well. This is inevitable
because what happens is, conway's law.
The team conway's law says, that organizations which
are designing systems are constrained
to produce designs which are copies of the
communication structures of their organization,
which means if a team is working on something.
This something gets closer together, and then
reuse gets even further, because some developers
change team and they start to use the framework
of the old team, and then we really have a big
ball of mud. Domain-Driven Design says don't do this.
Go for domain excellence, not for reuse. Let
teams build their own domain specific software
from UI to database. If we call up our
model of our software again that means,
no reuse in the domain application source code.
Here, each piece of software should be a specific
piece of software for its sub domains as
specifically as possible. But in the technical
part of the system, there we should definitely
do reuse, that's for sure, but not in the domain a
specific part. And finally I want to show you that
it is possible to find out where you stand when
it comes to modularization within your system. If
you want to know how modular your source code is.
Whether if it's microservices or monolith. We can
measure this with the modularity maturity index.
If the modularity is poor. The system is rated
zero to four. If the modularity is quite mediocre.
We give four to eight as great, and if the
modularity is good the system gets 8 to 10.
The x-axis represents just the time and
now I will show you some some systems.
You can see different cycles here, Each of which
stands for one system, so these are 22 systems
in different programming languages. Some are
in the red area, some in the yellow and some in
the green. And on the x-axis is just the time, this
was the first system, this is the second and so on.
The system up here was built in Java and has 40
million lines of code. It's very modular, very good.
This one, unfortunately, as well is Java, with a
very bad modularization. This one is Java
as well, with some, but not enough modularization
to arrive at the green area. This one is C#,
but this one up here is C#, too. So you can see,
that the programming language has little influence
on the modularity unfortunately. There's as
well PHP, TypeScript and PLSQL in there.
As the developers and architects have to take
care of the modularity ourself, how do we get to
this rating well. We meet with our clients and we
analyze their system for modularity with various
tools. You can see here, the Sonagraph, TeamScale,
Structure 101, the Sotograph and Lattix. All tools
that help us to find out about the modularity.
There's a quite complex algorithm to calculate
the modularity maturity in text. Of course, since
march 2020, our meetings are virtual as this one as well.
If you want to know more about Sustainable
Software Architecture and Domain-Driven Design.
Contact me via twitter or email, look at my
book and thank you very much for your attention.
Okay, thanks Carola for your visit and
informational whole speech. I really
find your speech very enjoyable, yeah.
Thank you mom, thank you. Yeah, yeah, and
now especially I love the metaphor of the tree.
You so far should root in the domain and your
modularity matrix that's really fun, and
really inspiring and thoughtful, yeah, okay.
Let me see if you have any questions,
please, please post your question
on the Slido, and you can upload your question
so that I can see the question better, okay.
So the first question is, okay this one. "How do you
imply this kind of method on a starup company?"
You have any experience to share?
Oh yeah, yeah, This is a perfect question, what it I understood
it rightly, it was about startup, was it? Yeah, Phone, no?
Yeah.
Okay it was about startup.
Because I can't see it on the screen at the
moment, so this is why I asked, okay.
Okay, startup.
Ah, startup I can see the word even your wonderful,
your wonderful language, yeah, okay so.
If, I mean in my company we start, of course, as
well new projects all the time, we create software
for our customers. And what I do is I get all
my colleagues trained so that they know how to
create good architecture, so a startup should as
well have well formed developers that
construct the new software that program, you know.
And then one thing that anybody today should do,
whatever software you write, you have to do test
first, or at least you have to write unit tests.
You know, maybe not before, but you have to write
them, and if your software is full of unit tests.
There's a high percentage of source code
tested with unit tests. Your architecture
will be better. This is an overall experience
that I made, whenever I looked at any software.
Because if you want to test something, you start
to create separate pieces, you know.
You can't have a tangled structure. This
is very difficult to test, so please, please.
Startups do tests, do unit tests and this will help
a lot, and then read books learn about modularity.
And your your software will live a long
time, so I hope this is a good help for the startup.
Yeah, test first.
Yes, thank you.
Sometimes, you know, you have to create something,
before you do the test, but test first is the best.
Read books, exactly, they all write it down in the chat.
Yeah, I totally agree. I think some good
practice applies everywhere, no better than a big
company or in the startup. Okay, I think we have
still have time for maybe two questions, so next
one, someone from anonymous, okay. She's very, he
or she is very curious about whether we can apply
DDD in agile. how to combine these two things to
build a more sustainable software? Could you share
some insights?
Yes, yes, my company is working agile
since the beginning, and agile actually fits very
very well with Domain-Driven Design, because
if you do agile, you have continuous
contact with your users. You after every
iteration, you represent what you've done,
and you discuss what what you can do next. And
this is actually what Domain-Driven Design wants.
Domain-Driven Design wants that we have a lot of
contact with our users that we discuss with them,
so that the developers get better into the
domain, understand more about the domain.
So these two ideas fit perfectly with each other.
There's no problem there, I can see no problem.
Yes that's a good news, yeah I think there's lots
of people, because lots of people in taiwan knows
about agile, so maybe it's a good starting point for them to access DDD.
Yes, yes.
Okay, I think we still have
time for the final question. The final question
is: "When transforming legacy system to microservice,
we find problems like how to break the monolith
into parts and keep the data consistency.", yeah.
Do you have any suggestion about this, about
how to do the migration or any tips?
Yeah, very good question, yes. It's a big problem
because you have to cut the thing as I showed you
on the slide, as well, down to the database and you
have to separate the database into different parts.
So you will have one database per microservice,
and of course this is scary in the beginning.
Because you think, oh my god I have a customer
here, and I mean you have seen it on my diagram, the
customer in the account management, the customer
in the credit and it's always the same person.
What does this mean, well, actually it's not such
a problem, because each bounded context works on a
part of the customer, that the other one is not
working on. And you can transport the data
from one database microservice to the other by
events and by what do you say,
by distributing the data from one microservice to
microservice. And actually, this is something
we do in huge companies anyway. We have a lot
of systems there and we always transport the
data about the customer from one system to the
other, so it's not such a scary thing. Of course,
you have to keep them consistent, and that's
sometimes it takes time to get all the systems
in sync. But you know, with Amazon, Netflix and all
those companies, there is no need to be consistent
everywhere in the same moment. You can have
some delay. It's not a real problem in general.
Okay, thank you very, very insightful. Yeah, and
they also raise my bills about your speech
talking about, sometimes maybe you should forget
about the micro service, maybe you should consider
more about your modularity and the context.
Yes.
Yeah, cool. Absolutely, thank you again. Yeah, thank
you again very much.
It was a pleasure.
And we are very honor to have you here, yeah, thank you, yeah.
Okay, so the session ends here. If you have any more
questions or if you want to have a talk with Carola,
you can go to the private room with her
and you can have a good talk. So thank you Carola again,
and the next session will start at 4:30, yeah.
Okay, 4:30. So the next speaker will be Luca.
So okay, see you, see you everyone, goodbye.
Bye bye! Thank you, thank you everyone.
Thank you.